come on
cars have always been a part of my
photography especially when I'm making
landscape photos within a city they end
up making their way into the photos a
lot of the times and to me when this is
successful the car will actually
complement the landscape that it's
sitting in but I've personally never set
out with the specific intentions of
focusing on photographing a car and I
think my first serious opportunity to do
this was when Road and track magazine
recently reached out to me and asked me
to photograph the Corvette Z06 in the
desert so today I want to share some
behind the scenes of this shoot with the
Corvette Z06 and share some of my
process behind photographing maybe one
of the coolest supercars to come out of
America in a very long time
this issue of rodent track magazine is
titled sacred ground and it's as much
about the cars as it is about the places
that are important to cars and car
enthusiasts and so for the Corvette Z06
I would be photographing it on the roads
of Anza Borrego where this car was
actually developed and perfected by
Aaron link who's the GM development
driver and he would be joining us on the
shoot as well before we get into the
shoot I want to share a little bit of
the planning and the pre-production that
goes into a project like this there's
two things I'll usually do I'll go on
Google Maps street view to find
interesting looking key points or
interesting overlooks and then to find
interesting like twisty roads I'll go on
Google Maps and just look at the shape
of the road itself find some nice curves
and see if there are any Vantage points
to photograph the car from in terms of
equipment I would be bringing my Mamiya
rz67 and my Mia 7 as a backup which as
you'll see in the video I'm very glad I
did bring a backup then finally I have
my digital camera just to test my flash
shots and to preview some images
foreign
all right
I really like the blue colors that are
going on from this early morning glow
especially with the orange car in there
it just complements each other very
nicely
foreign
we just shot some foggy photos of the
Corvette
uh like at the first light and now we're
at this beautiful viewpoint
to hopefully get some more photos of it
I'm really winging it because I'm
absolutely not a car photographer but
we're gonna see what we can make of it
here the light looks incredible and I
think if we just put the car in the good
light we'll get good photos so that's
the plan we're coming up to a Viewpoint
now the rz67 already crapped out on the
shoot it already decided to stop working
thank you
foreign with my flash here quite a bit
to kind of create some visual interest
different from the sunny images just to
give the editor something to play with
in the edit of the magazine create some
visually different looking images flash
is a great way to do that and there was
one flash shot in particular that stood
out to me which was actually a digital
photo of the interior of the car and it
really lit up the interior perfectly in
this like clinical way that shows like
the beautiful details of the stitching
and at the same time balanced with the
natural light is kind of this nice
mountainous landscape out the window and
I think this is a great shot because it
shows the interior but it also gets you
excited for these sacred roads that you
can see just out the window
thank you
foreign
s for the shoot was to have a lot of
motion in it so that the images really
had the feeling of driving the Z06 and
this was a real challenge for me
especially shooting on film I shot
anywhere between a 15th of a second and
a 60th of a second when I was trying to
get a motion blurry shot in the end this
just took quite a lot of film to commit
to getting that motion blur shot perfect
but in the end I think it was worth it
there's one shot specifically that I
think is my favorite from the whole
shoot where the Z06 is just moving
enough you can see the wheels are
spinning but the car is sharp and this
like gorgeous mountain landscape in the
background is slightly blurry but just
sharp enough I love the way this image
turned out
thank you
this was also a spot where we took some
portraits of Aaron Lincoln as I
mentioned before is the development
driver for GM he actually perfected this
car on these roads so to be able to
photograph him here with the car was
really special I used my flash in these
images and I got him sitting in the car
with the door open through the window
just trying to get a little bit of
variety here and I like the way these
looked but ultimately my favorite
portrait of Aaron ended up being the one
that we shot just after this at lunch
time when we sat down in a cafe and I
snapped some candid flash photos of him
drinking some coffee and it just ended
up being such a natural looking photo
after lunch I hopped inside the car for
a nice drive because I knew I wanted to
get some photos of the landscape moving
through the front windshield and out the
windows
thank you
the last missing piece of the shoot is
something that's almost required on any
Automotive shoot which is a rolling shot
of the car basically tracking the car
from another vehicle and so I was
hanging out the sunroof of my car while
Jake my buddy was driving and we were
following the Corvette down these desert
roads and this is a great way to get the
car still in the frame with the wheels
moving and the landscape blurred as the
car is going by my favorite one ended up
being this one with kind of a
interesting angle to it and I don't
usually do this but I think in this case
it added some energy to the shot and
added the excitement that it needed the
magazine is out and it looks beautiful
in print I think this project was
largely a success because of the very
clear direction of the editor Cassidy at
Road and track the way she requested a
lot of motion in the shots and she asked
for an emphasis on these sacred places
just as much as she wanted photos of the
car it really was a dream project for me
getting to combine like just my love for
cars and photography in one project
something that's really exciting is I
think maybe the best video I've ever
made for YouTube is coming out in a week
or maybe 10 days on the Porsche YouTube
channel it's a video where I basically
photograph all things Porsche we go to
the museum they're factories their
workshops we drive cars out on the roads
of Germany and that'll be out in a week
or so I think that's going to wrap it up
for this video thank you guys so much
for watching and finally thank you to
Squarespace for sponsoring this video
Squarespace is an incredible all-in-one
website building platform that you can
use to build your photography portfolio
online I've been using Squarespace for
so many years and they've made it so
easy to get a website up and running
with my photography so if that sounds
like something you're interested in you
can hit the link in my description for a
14 day free trial of Squarespace when
you're ready to launch go to
squarespace.com Willem for 10 off your
first purchase of a website or a domain
thank you guys so much for watching see
you next week peace
foreign